# ANFAAL FAISAL

Kalamazoo, MI 49006 (346) 204-1630 - afjdeveloper@gmail.com Website: https://afaisal.dev/

## PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Goal-oriented tech enthusiast with strong commitment to collaboration and solutionsoriented problem-solving. Who use's various software designs to develop customerfocused products and brands. Committed to high standards of web design, user experience, usability and speed for multiple types of end-users. Successful at maintaining customer satisfaction through effective customer support.

#### **EDUCATION**

Expected in 12/2021 Bachelor of Science: Computer Science with a minor in Communications

Western Michigan University - Kalamazoo, MI

06/2016

**High School Diploma** 

Wesgreen International School - Dubai

### WORK HISTORY

12/2018 to Current

# **Help Desk Student Lead**

# WMU Office Of Information and Technology - Kalamazoo, MI

- Trained and supported end-users with software, hardware and network standards and use processes
- Monitored problem management database and followed up with assigned personnel
- Followed up with clients to verify optimal customer satisfaction following support engagement and problem resolution
- Scheduled staff and delivered training materials and information
- Patched software and installed new versions to eliminate security problems and protect data
- DUPE Engaged end-users and answered questions via email, phone, website live chat and in forums
- Removed malware, ransomware and other threats from laptops and desktop
- Worked with students/staff customers to understand needs and provide technical service

#### 12/2018 to Current

# **Web Development Intern**

# S-Cube Technologies - Corona, CA

- Worked in streamlining workflow and process with UR-Health App.
- Improve user experience for pharmacy app using JavaScript, CSS and other JS frameworks like react/react native
- System Analyst and Liaison between Development team and end users
- QA/Testing for releasing apps to app store both android and iOS.
- Updating User statistics regarding usage, downloads and user experience. Specially identifying why user stopped using app.
- Help implementing Apple Pay for prescriptions as payment source.
- Power BI reports for management.

### 08/2018 to 02/2019 Alumni Ambassador

### WMU Alumni Association – Kalamazoo, MI

- Maintained excellent attendance record, consistently arriving to work on time
- Increased customer satisfaction by resolving donation issues
- Developed team communications and information for team meetings

#### 08/2018 to 01/2019 **Server**

# WMU Catering – Kalmazoo, MI

• Collaborated with kitchen team to support order preparation, manage efficient deliveries and minimize customer service issues by verifying meals

### 06/2018 to 07/2018 Project Management Intern

### **Rexel Middle East** – Dubai, United Arab Emirates

- Attended Health Safety and Environmental (HSE) training conducted by Chicago Bridge and Iron (CB&I) (McDermott) for their ongoing plastic factory project in Oman (Sohar)
- Supported project managers in managing schedules and milestones
- Coordinated internal resources and third-party vendors for flawless execution of projects
- Tracked project performance to analyze successful completion of short- and longterm goals
- Identified project scopes, constraints, risks and deadlines

# ACCOMPLISHMENTS

- WMU Racquetball Club E-board 2019-2020 Media Coordinator
- AUSMUN 2018 Secretariat of Human Rights Commission
- THIMUN Qatar 2015 Best Delegate Award in Human Rights Council
- DIFC Stock Market Simulation 2013 Top 50

# **SKILLS**

- AngularJS
- SQL
- HTML5
- Hypertext Preprocessor
- JavaScript
- IT Support
- Web Development

- JQuery
- Java
- Python
- React/React native
- Software Development
- Office 365
- Social Media Marketing